Welcome to EnglishClass101.com's "English in Three Minutes".
欢迎来到EnglishClass101.com的“三分钟英语”。
The fastest, easiest, and most fun way to learn English.
学英语的最快、最简单、最有趣的方式。
Hi, how's it going?
嗨，怎么样？
I'm Alisha. Nice to meet you!
我是Alisha。很高兴见到你！
In this series,
在这个系列中，
we're going to learn some easy ways to ask and answer common questions in English.
我们将学习一些用英语提问和回答常见问题的简单方法。
It's really useful, and it only takes three minutes!
这非常有用，只需要三分钟！
In this lesson,
在这节课中，
you're going to learn new, more common ways to ask and answer the question: "How are you?" in English.
你将学习用新的、更常见的方式在英语中提出和回答“你好吗？”这个问题。
You've probably learned "How are you?" and "I'm fine" in textbooks before,
你可能在教科书中学过“你好吗？”和“我很好”，
but in the United States,
但在美国，
people will usually ask this question and answer it in a different way.
人们通常会以不同的方式提问和回答这个问题。
First,
首先，
let's review.
让我们回顾一下。
If someone says:
如果有人说：
"How are you?"
“你好吗？”
You can say:
你可以说：
"I'm fine."
“我很好。”
(slow) I'm fine.
(慢速) 我很好。
Here are some other ways to answer:
以下是一些其他回答方式：
"Pretty good."
“挺好的。”
This means about the same thing as "I'm fine".
这意味着与“我很好”差不多。
(slow) Pretty good.
(慢速) 挺好的。
We also have:
我们还有：
"Not bad."
“还行。”
You can use this if you are feeling just okay, or so-so.
如果你感觉一般，或者说“so-so”可以使用这个。
(slow) Not bad.
(慢速) 还行。
Let's look at our question again: How are you?
让我们再看一下我们的问题：你好吗？
This is the most well-known way of asking how someone is.
这是询问别人状况最为人熟知的方式。
You could use it when you want to be polite.
你可以在想要礼貌地询问时使用它。
But now,
但现在，
let's look at some different ways to ask how someone is.
让我们看看一些不同的询问别人状况的方式。
These ways are more casual, and much more common.
这些方式更加随意，也更为常见。
First:
首先：
Hey, how's it going? (slow version added)
嘿，最近怎么样？（增加慢速版本）
You can answer this in many ways.
你可以用很多方式回答。
If you’re feeling good, you can say:
如果你感觉不错，你可以说：
"Good."
“好。”
(slow) Good.
(慢速) 好。
"Pretty good."
“挺好的。”
(slow) Pretty good.
(慢速) 挺好的。
"Not bad."
“还行。”
(slow) Not bad.
(慢速) 还行。
Once more:
再说一次：
"Good."
“好。”
"Pretty good."
“挺好的。”
"Not bad."
“还行。”
Here's a tip!
这里有一个提示！
Even though these answers mean the same thing as "I'm fine",
尽管这些回答的意思与“我很好”相同，
you can't answer "How's it going?" with "I'm fine."
但你不能用“我很好”回答“最近怎么样？”
It will sound a bit strange.
会听起来有点奇怪。
If you're not feeling good, you can say:
如果你感觉不好，你可以说：
"Not so good"
“不太好”
(slow) Not so good
(慢速) 不太好
"Not great"
“不太好”
(slow) Not great.
(慢速) 不太好。
or,
或者，
"Not so well".
“不太好”。
(slow) Not so well.
(慢速) 不太好。
Be careful:
要小心：
If you say one of these,
如果你说了其中一个，
the other person will usually ask,
对方通常会问，
"Why, what's wrong?" to be polite.
“怎么了，有什么问题吗？”是为了礼貌。
Then, you will have to explain!
然后，你就必须解释！
Another casual, but very common version of "How are you?" is "What's up?"
另一种随意但非常常见的“你好吗？”的说法是“最近怎么样？”
To reply, use a cheerful voice as you say:
要回答，用愉快的声音说：
"Not much!"
“没什么！”
(slow) Not Much
(慢速) 没什么
OR
或者
"Nothing much!"
“没什么！”
(slow) Nothing much!
(慢速) 没什么！
This means you're free and able to chat.
这意味着你有空聊天。
Since "What's up" is just another way of saying "Hello",
由于“最近怎么样”只是说“你好”的另一种方式，你也可以用
you can also reply with: "Hey!" or "Hi!"
“嘿！”或“你好！”
Now it's time for Alisha's Advice!
现在是Alisha的建议时间！
A lot of the time,
很多时候，
when we ask questions that mean "how are you?" in English,
当我们用英语问类似“你好吗？”的问题时，
we're not actually asking about the other person's health
我们实际上并不是在询问对方的健康状况
we're only asking to be polite!
我们只是为了礼貌而问！
You should think of these kinds of questions as another way of saying "Hello"
你应该把这类问题看作是说“你好”的另一种方式
a way for the conversation to get started
是对话开始的一种方式
instead of actual literal questions.
而不是实际的字面意义上的问题。
In fact, when someone asks you "what's up?"
事实上，当有人问你“最近怎么样？”时，
you don't even have to answer!
你甚至不必回答！
Just say "What's up?" in reply.
只需要回答“最近怎么样？”即可。
Do you know the difference between "What do you do?" and "What are you doing?"
现在，你知道“你是做什么的？”和“你在做什么？”之间的区别吗？
It's a little tricky,
这有点棘手，
but we'll explain it simply in the next English in 3 Minutes lesson!
但我们将在下一个“三分钟英语问题”课程中简单解释！
See you next time!
下次见！